Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research and Writing, 1919-1978; Series II; 36 linear feet (77 boxes)
  - Subject File
    - Labor, "Manuscript and notes in Progress": notes, draft, [1943] (Box 116, Folder 583)
    - Labor, "AFL-CIO Organizers' Union Row": research material, correspondence, 1958 (Box 116, Folder 584)
    - League for Cultural Freedom and Socialism: research material, mailing lists, 1939 (Box 116, Folder 585)
    - Levine, David: research material, notes, draft, 1969 (Box 116, Folder 586)
    - "Little Rock": research material, notes, 1956-1958 (Box 116, Folder 587)
    - London, "Reflections: notes & Raw Material for my column in Encounter (London)": research material, notes, drafts, 1956-1957 (Box 116, Folder 588)
    - "London": research material, notes, 1960-1961 (Box 116, Folder 589)
    - Lowell (James R.) Legal Defense Committee: research material, draft, correspondence, 1967 (Box 117, Folder 590)
    - Lung cancer
      - Research material, 1940-1954 (Box 117, Folder 591)
      - Research material, notes, 1945-1954 (Box 117, Folder 592)
      - Research material, 1950-1955 (Box 117, Folder 593)
      - Research material, notes, 1951-1954 (Box 117, Folder 594)
      - Research material, 1952-1953 (Box 117, Folder 595)
      - "Correspondence": research material, notes, correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 118, Folder 596)
      - "Second String Data": research material, notes, 1953-1955 (Box 118, Folder 597)
      - Research material, 1954 (Box 118, Folder 598)
    - Lynn case, "Legal documents": research material, notes, draft, 1942-1943 (Box 118, Folder 599)
      See also: box 30, folder 771 box 30, folder 771 box 30, folder 772 box 79, folder 169 box 79, folder 172
    - McCarthy, Joseph: research material, 1951-1955, 1952-1954 (Box 118, Folder 600-601)
    - McCarthy, Joseph: research material, notes, 1952-1954, 1966-1967 (Box 119, Folder 602-603)
    - McNamara, Robert: drafts, 1966-1967 (Box 119, Folder 604)
    - Mann, Thomas: research material, notes, 1936-1939 (Box 119, Folder 605)
    - "March on Washington Movement": research material, notes, correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 119, Folder 606)
      See also: box 7, folder 138 box 21, folder 546 box 42, folder 1034
    - Marxism: research material, notes, draft, [1940s] (Box 119, Folder 607)
    - Mass cultures, 1957-1959
      - Research material, 1957-1959 (Box 119, Folder 608)
      - Research material, 1961 (Box 120, Folder 609)
      - Research material, notes, 1961-1964, 1960-1962 (Box 120, Folder 610-610a)
      - Research material, notes, drafts, 1947-1973, 1955-1960 (Box 120, Folder 611-612)
    - Mass culture research material, notes, drafts, 1957-1959 (Box 120, Folder 613)
      See also: box 10, folder 235 box 30, folder 759-764 box 55, folder 1348
    - Mass culture, "Academicism and Avantgardism," "Role and Problems of U.S. Intellectuals," "Philistine Attacks on Avant Garde," "Follies and Failures of Avant Garde": research material, notes, 1945-1957 (Box 120, Folder 614)
    - Mass culture, "Advertising": research material, notes, 1953-1957 (Box 120, Folder 615)
    - Mass culture, "American Society": research material, notes, drafts, [1955-1959] (Box 121, Folder 616)
    - Mass culture, anti-Communist rally: notes, [1962-1963] (Box 121, Folder 617)
    - Mass culture, "Art and Architecture": research material, 1949-1962 (Box 121, Folder 618)
    - Mass culture, Simone de Beauvoir: research material, notes, draft, 1955 (Box 121, Folder 619)
    - Mass culture, "Bibliography": research material, notes, [1955-1959] (Box 121, Folder 620)
    - Mass culture, "Book Publishing": research material, 1941-1958 (Box 121, Folder 621)
    - Mass culture, "Businessmen and Culture": research material, notes, 1937-1940 (Box 121, Folder 622)
    - Mass culture, Bruce Catton: research material, notes, draft, 1957 (Box 121, Folder 623)
    - Mass culture, "Comics": research material, notes, 1941-1955 (Box 121, Folder 624)
    - Mass culture, communication: "Communication and Humanitas" by Leo Lowenthal, undated (Box 121, Folder 625)
    - Mass culture, "Detective Stories": research material, 1944-1955 (Box 121, Folder 626)
    - Mass culture, "General Theories": research material, 1963-1967 (Box 121, Folder 627)
    - Mass culture, "The Good -- Alive in Mass Culture": research material, notes, 1947-1957 (Box 121, Folder 628)
    - Mass culture, Ernest Hemingway: research material, notes, draft, correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 121, Folder 629)
    - Mass culture, "High Culture": research material, notes, 1941-1958 (Box 121, Folder 630)
    - Mass culture, "High Culture": research material, 1947-1965 (Box 121, Folder 631)
    - Mass culture, "High Culture individuals (Joyce, Eliot, etc.)": research material, 1940-1957 (Box 121, Folder 632)
    - Mass culture, "High Culture: Little Magazines": research material, 1938-1951 (Box 122, Folder 633)
    - Mass culture, "Humor," "British Humor," "The Past," "American Life in General": research material, 1936-1957 (Box 122, Folder 634)
    - Mass culture, "Institute for Creative Research Inc.: progress Report": research material, draft by Russell Davenport, 1952 December 1 (Box 122, Folder 635)
    - Mass culture, "Literature and General Culture": draft by Seymour Betsky, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 636)
    - Mass culture, "Low Culture": research material, 1956-1964 (Box 122, Folder 637)
    - Mass culture, "Magazines": research material, 1941-1950 (Box 122, Folder 638)
    - Mass culture, magazines, "Luce Papers": research material, 1938-1958 (Box 122, Folder 639)
    - Mass culture, magazines: draft, "Project: A New American Cultural Weekly", 1962 (Box 122, Folder 640)
    - Mass culture, magazines: "Random notes on H. W. Ross" by Geoffrey Hellman, 1965 May 14 (Box 122, Folder 641)
    - Mass culture, "Mass and Class": research material, 1963-1965 (Box 122, Folder 642)
    - Mass culture, "Masscult": research material, notes, drafts, 1948-1962 (Box 122, Folder 643)
    - Mass culture, "Masscult and Midcult": research material, notes, draft of talk, [1967-1969] (Box 122, Folder 644)
    - Mass culture, "Masses: Folkization or Attempt to Compensate in Fantasy for Lack of Real Community": research material, 1949-1957 (Box 122, Folder 645)
    - Mass culture, "Masses," "Historical Origins": research material, notes, drafts, 1935-1958 (Box 122, Folder 646)
    - Mass culture, "Midcult": research material, notes, 1958-1959 (Box 122, Folder 647)
    - Mass culture, "Miscellaneous Long Articles": research material, 1940-1957 (Box 123, Folder 648)
    - Mass culture, "Miscellaneous Long Articles -- (Hold)": research material, 1949-1957 (Box 123, Folder 649)
    - Mass culture, "Miscellaneous Long Articles -- (Hold)": research materials, notes, 1949-1954 (Box 123, Folder 650)
    - Mass culture, "Newspapers": research material, draft, 1936-1957 (Box 123, Folder 651)
    - Mass culture, "Obituaries": research material, 1940-1956 (Box 123, Folder 652)
    - Mass culture, "Science and Scientists": research material, notes, draft, 1938-1952 (Box 123, Folder 653)
    - Mass culture, "Sex": research material, notes, drafts, 1940-1959 (Box 123, Folder 654)
    - Mass culture, "Sports": research material, 1954-1955 (Box 123, Folder 655)
    - Mass culture, "Style": research material, notes, drafts, 1941-1957 (Box 123, Folder 656)
    - Mass culture, television, "Omnibus": research material, notes, 1952-1954 (Box 124, Folder 657)
      See also: box 5, folder 57 box 16, folder 415
    - Mass culture, "TV and Radio": research material, 1940-1963 (Box 124, Folder 658)
    - Mass culture, "TV and Radio": research material, notes, drafts, [1961] (Box 124, Folder 659)
    - Mass culture, " Tempo Presente article": research material, notes, 1963-1964 (Box 124, Folder 660)
      See also: box 94, folder 365
    - Mass culture, "Towards a Redefinition of Culture" (The American Academy of Arts and Sciences Conference, 1963 May 10-11): research material and drafts by: (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - James S. Ackerman (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Harvey Brooks (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Douglas Bush (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Benjamin DeMott Franklin L. Ford (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Stephen R. Graubard (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - William Letwin (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Harry Levin (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Herbert Marcuse (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Margaret Mead (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Robert S. Morrison (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Lewis Mumford (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - Talcott Parsons (Box 124, Folder 661)
      - I.A. Richards (Box 124, Folder 661)
    - Mass culture, "U.S.A. -- Mores": research material, notes, drafts, 1957-1958 (Box 124, Folder 662)
    - Mass culture, "Unsorted Articles and Clippings": research material, notes, drafts, 1941-1959 (Box 125, Folder 663)
    - Mass culture, "Used in Talks -- Unsorted": research material, notes, 1936-1958 (Box 125, Folder 664)
    - Mass culture, "War and Culture": research material, 1939-1942 (Box 125, Folder 665)
    - Mass culture, "Colin Wilson and Other Angry Young Men": research material, notes, 1957-1958 (Box 125, Folder 666)
    - "Mission to Moscow": research material, 1943 (Box 125, Folder 667)
    - Mitchell (David) draft resistance case: research material, 1966 (Box 125, Folder 668)
    - Monroe Defense Committee: research material, 1961-1962 (Box 125, Folder 669)
    - Muste, A.J.: "notes for An Article on", [1967?] (Box 125, Folder 670)
    - "National Caucus of Labor Committees v. Communist Party": research material, 1972 (Box 125, Folder 671)
    - National Conference for New Politics
      - Research material, 1966-1967 (Box 125, Folder 672)
      - Research material, 1967 (Box 126, Folder 673-674)
    - National Conference for New Politics: research material, notes, drafts, proof, 1967 (Box 126, Folder 675)
      See also: box 38, folder 960
    - National Foundation for the Arts and Humanities: research material, 1965 (Box 126, Folder 676)
    - New Deal, "Bibliography": notes, [post-1941] (Box 126, Folder 677)
    - "New Left": clippings, 1966-1970 (Box 126, Folder 678)
    - "New Left": research material, notes, 1966-1970 (Box 126, Folder 679)
    - "New Left: YMHA Talks": notes, drafts, transcript of panel discussion with:, 1967 (Box 127, Folder 680)
      - D. Macdonald (Box 127, Folder 680)
      - Tom Hayden (Box 127, Folder 680)
      - Ivanhoe Donaldson (Box 127, Folder 680)
      - Richard Rovere (Box 127, Folder 680)
    - New York City politics: research material, 1973 (Box 127, Folder 681)
    - The New York Civil Liberties Union: research material, correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 127, Folder 682)
    - The New York Times: draft parodies by Esquire staff, 1969 (Box 127, Folder 683)
    - Nixon, Richard: research material, notes, 1973 (Box 127, Folder 684)
    - Pacifism: research material, 1932-1955, undated (Box 127, Folder 685)
    - Pacifism, "World Community": research material, 1946-1949 (Box 127, Folder 686)
    - Pacifism: research material, notes, draft, 1947-1948 (Box 127, Folder 687)
    - Pacifism: research material, notes, drafts, correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 127, Folder 688)
      See also: box 35, folder 892 box 55, folder 1337-1338
    - Pacifism, "World Community": mailing from UNESCO, 1968 (Box 127, Folder 689)
    - Pacifism: research material, 1968-1970 (Box 127, Folder 690)
    - "Politics -- 1930's and 1940's": research material, notes, drafts (Box 128, Folder 691)
    - "Politics -- 1950's": research material, notes, drafts, 1950-1958 (Box 128, Folder 692)
    - Politics, 1960s: research material, 1964-1965 (Box 128, Folder 693)
    - "Proletariat": research material, notes, drafts, 1946-1948 (Box 128, Folder 694)
    - Racism: research material, 1960-1970 (Box 128, Folder 695)
    - Rahv, Philip: notes on his death, 1973 (Box 128, Folder 696)
    - "Refugees": research material, notes, 1938-1943 (Box 128, Folder 697)
    - Richardson, Henry Handel: "notes on H.H. Richardson,", undated (Box 128, Folder 698)
    - "Rights of Mental Patients"
      - Research material, 1972-1973 (Box 128, Folder 699)
      - Research material, notes, 1972-1973 (Box 129, Folder 700-701)
    - Scales, Junius: research material, correspondence, 1962 (Box 129, Folder 702)
      See also: box 45, folder 1109
    - Serge, Victor: visa applications, affidavits, 1940 (Box 129, Folder 703)
    - Sobell, Morton: research material, notes, 1957-1967 (Box 129, Folder 704)
    - Sobell, Morton: research material, notes, drafts, correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 129, Folder 705)
      See also: box 24, folder 630 box 26, folder 691 box 45, folder 1109
    - "Space, History": research material, 1958-1959 (Box 129, Folder 706)
    - "Spooks," spiritualism and extra-sensory perception: research material, notes, 1955-1960 (Box 129, Folder 707)
      See also: box 35, folder 891
    - Steel: "Industry pamphlets", 1915-1936 (Box 129, Folder 708)
    - Steel, "Steel, Labor, the NIRA and the Amalgamated Association," by Harold Ruttenberg: notes, draft, 1934 (Box 130, Folder 709)
    - Steel: research material, 1934-1937 (Box 130, Folder 710)
    - Steel: research material, notes, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 711)
      See also: box 16, folder 422
    - Steel: research material, notes, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 712)
    - Steel: notes, drafts, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 713)
    - Steel: "U.S. Steel Series in Fortune -- Part IV (last) -- original Ms.": drafts, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 714)
    - Steel, "U.S. Steel Ms.": draft, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 715-716)
      See also: box 78, folder 122
    - Steel, "Miscellaneous: Live—Not Yet Sorted": research material, notes, 1936-1937 (Box 130, Folder 717)
    - Steel: notes, drafts, 1936-1937 (Box 131, Folder 718-719)
    - Steel, "Ms. in Progress": notes, drafts, 1936-1937 (Box 131, Folder 720)
    - Steel, "Abortive Book on Steel Industry (Ms. of chapters II and III)":drafts, 1936-1937 (Box 131, Folder 721)
    - Steel: notes, drafts, 1936-1938 (Box 131, Folder 722)
    - Steel: annotated bibliography, 1936-1938 (Box 131, Folder 723-724)
    - Steel, "Steel Towns": notes, drafts, [1937] (Box 132, Folder 725)
    - Steel: notes, drafts, 1937-1938 (Box 132, Folder 726)
    - Steel: correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 132, Folder 727)
      See also: box 50, folder 1213
    - Steel: research material, notes, 1937-1939 (Box 132, Folder 728)
    - Steel: notes, drafts, [1938] (Box 132, Folder 729)
    - Talese, Gay, "notes for review in NYRB he didn't write": research material, notes, drafts, 1965-1969 (Box 132, Folder 730)
    - Television: research material, notes, 1962-1965 (Box 132, Folder 731)
    - Thomas, Norman: research material, draft, [1950], 1964 (Box 132, Folder 732)
    - Triple Revolution, Ad Hoc Committee on the: research material, 1964 (Box 132, Folder 733)
      See also: box 34, folder 869
    - U.S.S.R.: research material, notes, 1937-1951 (Box 132, Folder 734)
    - U.S.S.R.: research material, 1938-1949 (Box 132, Folder 735)
    - U.S.S.R.
      - Research material, notes, 1948-1949, undated (Box 133, Folder 736)
      - Research material, notes, drafts, 1939-1949 (Box 133, Folder 737)
      - notes, undated (Box 133, Folder 738)
      - notes, drafts, undated (Box 133, Folder 739)
    - U.S.S.R., culture
      - Research material, notes, 1934-1956 (Box 133, Folder 740)
      - Research material, 1936-1956 (Box 133, Folder 741)
      - Research material, 1936-1957 (Box 134, Folder 742)
      - Research material, notes, 1938-1941, 1958-1959 (Box 134, Folder 743)
    - U.S.S.R., culture: notes, drafts, undated (Box 134, Folder 744)
      See also: Series I, General, Daniel Bell (enclosing manuscript by Jane Zielonko)
    - U.S.S.R., "Mass Culture":
      - Research material, notes, drafts, 1946-1957 (Box 134, Folder 745)
      - Research material, notes, 1947-1957 (Box 134, Folder 746)
    - U.S.S.R., "Metaphysics of Bureaucracy": research material, notes, drafts, 1946-1949 (Box 134, Folder 747)
    - U.S.S.R., Moscow trials: research materials, 1937-1941 (Box 134, Folder 748)
    - U.S.S.R., Boris Pasternak: drafts of open letter to the Union of Soviet Writers, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 749)
    - U.S.S.R., Andrei Sinyavsky/Abram Tertz trial: research material, notes, 1965-1966 (Box 134, Folder 750)
    - "U.S.A. -- Meyers and Pauley Scandals, 1947-1948": research material (Box 135, Folder 751)
    - The Victorian Society: society publications, 1962-1971 (Box 135, Folder 752)
    - Vietnam
      - Research material, 1964-1965 April-August (Box 135, Folder 753-754)
      - notes, draft of "1965 Talk at Ryan Meeting", 1965 August 12 (Box 135, Folder 755)
      - Research material, correspondence with political action groups, 1965 October-1966 (Box 135, Folder 756)
      - Research material, correspondence with political action groups, 1967 January-May (Box 135, Folder 757)
      - Research material, correspondence with political action groups, 1967 June-October 18 (Box 135, Folder 758)
      - Research material, 1967 October 19-21 (Box 135, Folder 759)
      - Research material, correspondence with political action groups, 1967 October 22-November (Box 136, Folder 760)
      - Research material, notes, correspondence, 1967 December (Box 136, Folder 761)
      - Draft, correspondence, 1968 January-May (Box 136, Folder 762)
    - Vietnam: research material, 1968 April-July (Box 136, Folder 763)
    - Vietnam
      - Research material, notes, correspondence, draft letters of tax refusal, 1968 August-1969 November 14 (Box 136, Folder 764)
      - Research material, notes, drafts, correspondence, 1969 November 15 (Box 136, Folder 765)
      - Clippings, 1965-1967 (Box 136, Folder 766)
      - Research material, notes; drafts, correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 136, Folder 767)
      - Clippings, 1965-1968 (Box 137, Folder 768)
      - Research material, 1969-1973, undated (Box 137, Folder 769-771)
    - Vietnam: research material, notes, draft, undated (Box 137, Folder 772)
      See also: box 10, folder 241; box 16, folder 403; box 23, folder 586; box 31, folder 779-780; box 31, folder 774; box 124, folder 661; box 35, folder 892; box 48, folder 1175; box 55, folder 1337-1338
    - Vietnam: research material and "Mary McCarthy MS?", 1965 (Box 137, Folder 773)
    - Vietnam, Assembly of Men and Women in the Arts, Concerned with Vietnam: research material, correspondence, 1967 (Box 137, Folder 774)
    - Vietnam, "RESIST": research material, correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 137, Folder 775)
    - Vietnam, "The Resistance": research material, correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 137, Folder 776)
    - Vietnam, "A Declaration of Peace to the People of Vietnam": research material, notes, draft, correspondence, 1970 (Box 138, Folder 777)
    - "Violence: The Guilty Bystander": research material, 1962-1964 (Box 138, Folder 778)
    - "War Crimes": clippings, 1945-1951 (Box 138, Folder 779)
    - Warren Commission Report, "notes for review of Mark Lane": research material, notes, drafts, 1965-1967 (Box 138, Folder 780)
    - Wilson, Edmund: research material, 1950-1951, 1955, 1957 (Box 138, Folder 781)
    - Wisconsin (University of) faculty trial: research material, notes, 1970-1971 (Box 138, Folder 782)
      See also: box 145-146, folder 76-84
    - Works Progress Administration
      - Clippings, 1935-1939, 1937-1941 (Box 138, Folder 783-784)
      - Research material, notes, drafts, [1938] (Box 139, Folder 785-786)
    - World War I: notes, undated (Box 139, Folder 787)
    - Yale, fire in the Art and Architecture Building: notes, 1969 (Box 139, Folder 788)
    - Yale, May Day
      - Research material, 1970 (Box 139, Folder 789-790)
      - Research material, notes, 1970 (Box 139, Folder 791)
    - Miscellaneous research material, 1949-1977 (Box 139, Folder 792)
- Teaching and Lectures, 1948-1977; Series III; 3 linear feet (7 boxes)
  The arrangement is alphabetical by the name of the institution. The only courses and lectures named in the folder listing are those for which there are notes, drafts, substantive correspondence, or other important papers.
  - Ad - Am (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - An-Au (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - Asher, Godfrey & Franklin, Inc., radio debate program: correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - B (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Bard College, "Mass Culture": administrative records, correspondence, 1958 (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Brandeis University National Women's Committee, "The Crisis in American Culture": draft, correspondence, 1964 January 7 (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - The British Broadcasting Corporation, "Asking the World": transcript, correspondence, 1960 April 3 (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Ca - Ce (Box 140, Folder 8)
  - University of California, Santa Cruz, Adlai E. Stevenson College, "History and Criticism of Cinema": notes, correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 140, Folder 9)
  - Ch - Col (Box 140, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago, "The New Cinema": correspondence, 1963 December 3 (Box 140, Folder 11)
  - Colgate University, Humanities Visiting Committee: notes, correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 140, Folder 12)
  - Colorado State University, "Eisenstein": correspondence, 1963 (Box 140, Folder 13)
  - Columbia University, seminar on non-fiction writing: correspondence, 1965 (Box 140, Folder 14)
  - Com - Cou (Box 141, Folder 15)
  - D - E (Box 141, Folder 16)
  - Conference on the Status of Soviet Jews See: Series I
    See: box 52, folder 1262
  - F (Box 141, Folder 17)
  - G (Box 141, Folder 18)
  - Georgetown University, "Our Invisible Poor": notes, drafts, correspondence, 1964 (Box 141, Folder 19)
  - H (Box 141, Folder 20)
  - Hofstra University, "American Political Fiction" and "Edgar Allan Poe": administrative records, notes, correspondence, 1969 Fall (Box 141, Folder 21)
  - I (Box 141, Folder 22)
  - University of Illinois, Socialist Study Club, address on Henry Wallace (cancelled): correspondence, 1968 (Box 141, Folder 23)
    See also: box 47, folder 1144
  - University of Illinois, Miller professorship, (rejected):Correspondence, draft of refusal to sign loyalty oath, 1963 (Box 141, Folder 23)
  - International Design Conference, Aspen: notes, drafts, 1964 (Box 141, Folder 24)
    See also: box 37, folder 949
  - J (Box 141, Folder 25)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, Conference on Moral Standards: correspondence, 1953 (Box 141, Folder 26)
  - K (Box 141, Folder 27)
  - Kenyon College, "The New Left and the Old Left": notes, correspondence, 1969 February 25 (Box 141, Folder 28)
  - L (Box 141, Folder 29)
  - Long Island University, Southampton College, Visiting Professor, Great Scholars Program, "Political Trends in the Arts": notes, draft, correspondence, 1970, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 30)
  - M (Box 142, Folder 3l)
  - University of Maryland, "The Nazi Extermination of the European Jews: The Problem of Explanation": correspondence, 1965 May 2 (Box 142, Folder 32)
    See also: box 6, folder 98 box 40, folder 998
  - University of Michigan, "Building the Great Society": correspondence, 1965 (Box 142, Folder 33)
  - University of Michigan, Writer-in-Residence Program: correspondence, 1967 (Box 142, Folder 33)
  - Mount Holyoke College, "U.S.A. or U.S.S.R.?" (debate with Norman Mailer): notes, correspondence, 1952, 1965 (Box 142, Folder 34)
    See also: box 32, folder 804
  - Na (Box 142, Folder 35)
  - Ne (Box 142, Folder 36)
  - City University of New York, John Jay College of Criminal Justice: administrative records correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 142, Folder 37)
  - City University of New York, John Jay College of Criminal Justice, "American Political Fiction": administrative records, student papers, 1975 (Box 142, Folder 38)
  - City University of New York, John Jay College of Criminal Justice, "Film History": administrative records, notes, student papers, 1975-1976 (Box 142, Folder 39)